

Renosh kurian

E-mail: renosh_k@yahoo.com Website: Linkedin profile: renosh-

kurian-56739b34

Phone: +919778261867 Address: Bangalore

Career summary

A highly motivated, seasoned, resulted oriented professional with 14 years work of experience in sales and business development of IoT powered automation, Fire protection, Electronic security system (CCTV, Access control), PAVA in Middle east and India

Professional Experience

Zenatix Solutions, Bangalore

March 2021 — Dec 2021

Regional Manager

Zenatix is a leading organisation predominantly into IoT based automation and energy management.

Products & Solution: IoT based Automation, energy management, Smart BMS, Integrated smart facility management

- Managed the business for entire south India and handled a team of 4
- Closely engaged with key consultants, system integrators and end-users to promote and create demand for the solution.
- Hired and trained 2 potential and high performing sales person to the team
- Successfully added 10+ new key accounts from Retail, Hospitality, Healthcare, QSR chain.
- Achieved 15% YoY growth in the sales from existing and new created accounts.

Johnson controls, Qatar

Oct 2019 — Sept 2020

Regional Sales Manager

Regional responsibility for sales and business development for Tyco security systems covering Qatar, Kuwait.

Products & Solutions: CCTV, Access control - Software house, Kantech, CEM system, Integrated security solution...

- Built and developed a strong channel partner network in the assigned territory.
- Contributed to the development of Tyco security portfolio proposition through excellent knowledge of the market, products, competitors and understanding of the customer changing requirements.
- Worked closely with the marketing team to conduct roadshows, seminars/ webinars which helped in market reach and brand building.
- Develop short and long term goals, targets and delegate them appropriately to the team, evaluate business performance, provide trainings etc
- Successfully achieved over 100% of the assigned AOP for Qatar and Kuwait.

Honeywell, Qatar

May 2013 — Oct 2019

Regional Sales manager- ME

Regional responsibility of Honeywell portfolio of products and solutions.

Renosh kurian

Products & Solutions: Honeywell Fire system (Esser, GENT, Notifier), PAVA, CCTV, Access control, Prowatch

- Managed and expanded potential channel partner network in all the assigned region. Managed 30+ channel partners.
- Actively engaged with marketing team to develop Honeywell portfolio in the assigned region by organising technical workshops/ seminars which helped in the early customer engagement and getting specified in the projects.
- Responsible for the P&L for the region. Hired, train and coach the sales team to deliver expected results.
- Generated and maintained a strong pipeline of opportunities (5x of AOP)
- Successfully maintained high performance by achieving over 100% of the target with 10-15% YoY growth

Kidde, Qatar

Aug 2010 — Apr 2013

Sales Manager

Kidde is the subsidiary of UTC fire & security (USA). In my role, I had managed the sale and business development of all the fire & security products in Qatar which includes Marioff HiFog water misting system, Autronica fire & Gas system, GST fire alarm system, Angus Fire systems, Kidde fire suppression

Telectron, Abu- Dhabi

Nov 2007 — July 2010

Project engineer

Worked as projects engineer in the Fire & Gas division.

- Maintains projects schedule by monitoring projects progress, co-ordinating site activities, review of design, specification, scheduling changes and recommending action.
- Projects managed include.
- 1. Fire alarm and suppression system at Abu Dhabi national refinery, Takreer.
- 2. Fire alarm and suppression systems at Safer exploration oil company (SEPOC), Yemen
- 3. Fire suppression system at Abu Dhabi international airport

Skills

- Sales & Business development
- Team player & Performance based management approach
- Brand building
- Effective communication

Education

Bachelors in Engineering (BE)

2002 - 2006

Rajiv Ghandi institute of technology, Bangalore

Dip. Fire & Safety management

2019 - 2020

Bharath Sevak samaj

Personal details

DOB: 10-May-1984 Marital status: Married

Languages: English, Malayalam, Hindi

Renosh kurian 2